# Danyang Zhuo

Assistant Professor Department of Computer Science Trinity College of Arts and Sciences Duke University December 10, 2021
308 Research Dr
Durham, NC 27705
danyang@cs.duke.edu
https://danyangzhuo.com

#### **Research Interests**

I do research broadly in computer systems, including operating systems, distributed systems, and computer networks, with a focus on the design and implementation of data center systems to support today's increasingly data-intensive applications (e.g., deep learning, big data analytics, packet processing). My approaches include software architecture design, programming languages, and machine learning.

#### Education

University of Washington – Seattle

Seattle, Washington

Ph.D. in Computer Science and Engineering

Sep 2013 - Aug 2019

- Dissertation: Practical, Efficient, and Reliable Data Center Communication.

- Advisors: Thomas E. Anderson, Arvind Krishnamurthy

University of Illinois - Urbana Champaign

Urbana, Illinois

 $B.S.\ in\ Electrical\ Engineering$ 

Advisor: Nitin Vaidya

Aug 2009 - May 2013

## **Professional Experience**

Duke University

Assistant Professor of Computer Science

University of California – Berkeley

Postdoctoral Researcher

- Advisor: Ion Stoica

Microsoft Research

Contractor (through Populous Group)

Microsoft Research

Research Intern

Google

Software Development Engineering Intern

Amazon

Software Development Engineering Intern

Microsoft

• Software Development Engineering Intern

Durham, North Carolina

Jul 2020 - now

Berkeley, California

Sep 2019 - Jun 2020

Redmond, Washington Oct 2015 - Feb 2017

Redmond, Washington Jun 2015 - Sep 2015

Mountain View, California

and the second

Sep 2014 - Mar 2015

Seattle, Washington

May 2013 - Sep 2013

Redmond, Washington

May 2012 - Aug 2012

#### **Awards**

Meta Research Award	021
Amazon Research Award	021
IBM Academic Award	021
FAST Best Paper Award	021
University of Washington Madrona Prize Runner-Up	018
University of Washington Hacherl Endowed Fellowship	014
Rank 146th in the William Lowell Putnam Mathematical Competition	012

#### **Publications**

#### Conference Papers

- 1. Xinhao Kong, Yibo Zhu, Huaping Zhou, Zhuo Jiang, Jianxi Ye, Chuanxiong Guo, Danyang Zhuo. *Collie: Finding Performance Anomalies in RDMA Subsystems*. The 19th USENIX Symposium on Networked Systems Design and Implementation (NSDI), 2022.
- 2. Jingrong Chen, Hong Zhang, Wei Zhang, Liang Luo, Jefferey Chase, Ion Stoica, Danyang Zhuo. NetHint: White-Box Networking for Multi-Tenant Data Centers. The 19th USENIX Symposium on Networked Systems Design and Implementation (NSDI), 2022.
- 3. Shunhua Jiang, Yunze Man, Zhao Song, Zheng Yu, Danyang Zhuo. Fast Graph Neural Tangent Kernel via Kronecker Sketching. The 36th AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI), 2022.
- 4. Danyang Zhuo, Kaiyuan Zhang, Zhuohan Li, Siyuan Zhuang, Stephanie Wang, Ang Chen, Ion Stoica. *Rearchitecting In-Memory Object Stores for Low Latency*. The 48th International Conference on Very Large Data Bases (VLDB), 2022.
- 5. Zhuohan Li, Siyuan Zhuang, Shiyuan Guo, Danyang Zhuo, Hao Zhang, Dawn Song, Ion Stoica. TeraPipe: Token-Level Pipeline Parallelism for Training Large-Scale Language Models. The 38th International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML), 2021.
- 6. Siyuan Zhuang, Zhuohan Li, Danyang Zhuo, Stephanie Wang, Eric Liang, Robert Nishihara, Philipp Moritz, Ion Stoica. *Hoplite: Efficient and Fault-Tolerant Collective Communication for Task-Based Distributed Systems*. In Proceedings of the Conference of the ACM Special Interest Group on Data Communication (SIGCOMM), 2021.
- 7. Shumo Chu, Danyang Zhuo, Elaine Shi, T-H. Hubert Chan. Differentially Oblivious Database Joins: Overcoming the Worst-Case Curse of Fully Oblivious Algorithms. The 2nd Information-Theoretic Cryptography conference (ITC), 2021.
- 8. Sitan Chen, Xiaoxiao Li, Zhao Song, Danyang Zhuo. On InstaHide, Phase Retrieval, and Sparse Matrix Factorization. The 9th International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR), 2021.
- 9. Samantha Miller, Kaiyuan Zhang, Mengqi Chen, Ryan Jennings, Ang Chen, Danyang Zhuo, Thomas Anderson. *High Velocity Kernel File Systems with Bento*. The 19th USENIX Conference on File and Storage Technologies (FAST), 2021.

  Best Paper Award.

- 10. Lianmin Zheng, Chengfan Jia, Minmin Sun, Zhao Wu, Cody Hao Yu, Ameer Haj-Ali, Yida Wang, Jun Yang, Danyang Zhuo, Koushik Sen, Joseph E. Gonzalez, Ion Stoica. Ansor: Generating High-Performance Tensor Programs for Deep Learning. The 14th USENIX Symposium on Operating Systems Design and Implementation (OSDI), 2020.
- 11. Kaiyuan Zhang, Danyang Zhuo, Arvind Krishnamurthy. *Gallium: Automated Software Middlebox Offloading to Programmable Switches*. In Proceedings of the Conference of the ACM Special Interest Group on Data Communication (SIGCOMM), 2020.
- 12. Kaiyuan Zhang, Danyang Zhuo, Aditya Akella, Arvind Krishnamurthy, Xi Wang. Automated Verification of Customizable Middlebox Properties with Gravel. The 17th USENIX Symposium on Networked Systems Design and Implementation (NSDI), 2020.
- 13. Danyang Zhuo, Kaiyuan Zhang, Yibo Zhu, Hongqiang Harry Liu, Matthew Rockett, Arvind Krishnamurthy, Thomas Anderson. *Slim: OS Kernel Support for a Low-Overhead Container Overlay Network*. The 16th USENIX Symposium on Networked Systems Design and Implementation (NSDI), 2019.
- 14. Danyang Zhuo, Monia Ghobadi, Ratul Mahajan, Klaus-Tycho Förster, Arvind Krishnamurthy and Thomas E. Anderson. *Understanding and Mitigating Packet Corruption in Data Center Networks*. In Proceedings of the Conference of the ACM Special Interest Group on Data Communication (SIGCOMM), 2017.
- 15. Danyang Zhuo, Monia Ghobadi, Ratul Mahajan, Amar Phanishayee, Xuan Kelvin Zou, Hang Guan, Arvind Krishnamurthy and Thomas E. Anderson. *RAIL: A Case for Redundant Arrays of Inexpensive Links in Data Center Networks*. The 14th USENIX Symposium on Networked Systems Design and Implementation (NSDI), 2017.
- 16. Vincent Liu, Danyang Zhuo, Simon Peter, Arvind Krishnamurthy and Thomas E. Anderson. Subways: A Case for Redundant, Inexpensive Data Center Edge Links. The 13th International Conference on emerging Networking Experiments and Technologies (CoNEXT), 2015.

#### Workshop Papers

- 1. John Snyder, Alvin Lebeck, Danyang Zhuo. *RDMA Congestion Control: It's Only for the Compliant*. Cloud@MICRO, 2021.
- 2. Jialin Li, Samantha Miller, Danyang Zhuo, Ang Chen, Jon Howell, Thomas Anderson. *An Incremental Path Towards a Safe OS Kernel.* The 18th Workshop on Hot Topics in Operating Systems (HotOS), 2021.
- Samantha Miller, Kaiyuan Zhang, Danyang Zhuo, Shibin Xu, Arvind Krishnamurthy, Thomas Anderson. Practical Safe Linux Kernel Extensibility. The 17th Workshop on Hot Topics in Operating Systems (HotOS), 2019.
- 4. Danyang Zhuo, Qiao Zhang, Xin Yang, Vincent Liu. Canaries in the Network. The 15th ACM Workshop on Hot Topics in Networks (HotNets), 2016.
- 5. Danyang Zhuo, Qiao Zhang, Vincent Liu, Arvind Krishnamurthy, Thomas E. Anderson. *Rack-level Congestion Control*. The 15th ACM Workshop on Hot Topics in Networks (HotNets), 2016.
- 6. Danyang Zhuo, Qiao Zhang, Dan Ports, Arvind Krishnamurthy, Thomas E. Anderson. *Machine Fault Tolerance for Reliable Datacenter Systems*. The 5th Asia-Pacific Workshop on Systems (APSys), 2014.

#### **Invited Papers**

1. Samantha Miller, Kaiyuan Zhang, Mengqi Chen, Ryan Jennings, Ang Chen, Danyang Zhuo, Thomas Anderson. *High Velocity Kernel File Systems with Bento*. USENIX ;login:, 2021.

#### **Patents**

1. Monia Ghobadi, Ratul Mahajan, Amar Phanishayee, Danyang Zhuo, Xuan Kelvin Zou. *Data Center Topology Having Multiple Classes of Reliability*. US Patent 20170302565A1. WIPO Patent 2017180450A1.

### **Students**

Current PhD Students: Jingrong Chen, Xinhao Kong, Yongji Wu Current Master Students: Guozhen She, Zhangzhang Yue, Wei Zhang

Current Interns: Baocheng Sun

#### **Invited Talk**

• Collie: Finding Performance Anomalies in RDMA Subsystems.	
– Microsoft Azure	Sep 2021
• Towards Efficient Cloud Systems for Data-Intensive Applications.	
– Rice University	Jun 2021
– Duke CS+ Undergraduate Summer Resarch Program	Jun 2021
– IBM	Feb 2021
• Towards Efficient and Reliable Data Center Systems.	
- Yale University	Apr 2019
- Purdue University	Apr 2019
- University of Virginia	Mar 2019
- Duke University	Mar 2019
- Rutgers University	Mar 2019
- Microsoft Research	Mar 2019
- Pennsylvania State University	Feb 2019
- University of Minnesota	Feb 2019
• Slim: OS Kernel Support for a Low-Overhead Container Overlay Network.	
- Princeton University	Jun 2020
— University of California - Berkeley	Nov 2019
- USENIX NSDI	Feb 2019
• Understanding and Mitigating Packet Corruption in Data Center Networks.	
- ACM SIGCOMM	Aug 2017

## **Teaching**

- Spring 2022: Data Center Systems (CompSci 590.04)
- Fall 2021: Introduction to Operating Systems (CompSci 310)
- Fall 2020: Advanced Operating Systems (CompSci 510)

### **Service**

#### **Program Committee**

• 2022: APNET, FAST, NSDI, SIGCOMM

• 2021: CoNEXT

• 2020: SIGCOMM